# DANIEL CHIU

### Austin, TX 78727 | (H) (512) 921-4843 | (C) (512) 921-4843 | cycdaniel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chiudaniel/ GitHub: https://github.com/DChiuIT9

# **Professional Summary**

Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users.

# **Skills**

- Certified Professional Web Developer
- Full-stack web development
- Troubleshooting & Website Optimization

• HTML/CSS/JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Python, C#

## Work History

#### Full-Stack Web Developer

08/2019 to 11/2019

**UT Austin** – Austin, TX

- Utilized Visual Studio Code to design and develop 20+ web applications deploying them to GitHub/Heroku
- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites
- Created eye-catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently
- Designed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Firefox, Chrome, and Safari
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment
- Collaborated with software engineers on projects to gain exposure to real-world workflow experience

### Senior Accountant

02/2017 to 08/2019

#### **Southwest Kev Programs** – Austin, TX

- Implemented use of various software to enter project data, analyze and track budgets, evaluate project costs and monitor performance trends
- Handled month-end and year-end end finances by managing and reporting fixed assets and other data
- Reviewed budgets, including capital appropriations and operating budgets, and communicated findings to senior management
- Prepared accounts for industry audits and supported audit process
- Automated manual review process before payroll run by customizing exception reports in ERP software
- Investigated and resolved variances in digital and physical records to promote record integrity
- Developed reconciliation processes for A/P and A/R department to identify discrepancies which resulted in tremendous time saving

#### **Financial Accountant**

04/2014 to 02/2017

## Southwest Key Programs – Austin, TX

- Led daily general ledger entries, using double-entry accounting method and check backs
- Mitigated impacts on financial accounting and business operations by working proactively to identify and resolve strategic concerns
- Reconciled credit card transactions on bank statement against the transactions processed in the accounting system for over \$20MM
- Streamlined bank reconciliation procedures which resulted in an increase of accuracy

## Education

Certificate: Full-Stack Web Developer Boot Camp Certificate

11/2019

**University of Texas At Austin - Austin, TX** 

**BBA**: Finance 12/2012

Texas State University - San Marcos, TX